YONAH KARP

Software Developer since 2016

(516) 428 4526

karp.yoni@gmail.com

♀ Inwood, NY 11096

yonahkarp.com

in linkedin.com/in/yonah-karp

🕠 github.com/yonahkarp

♣ ABOUT ME

Software Developer with 6+ years professional experience.

Genuinely enjoys programming, hard worker, fast and avid learner, capable and persistent problem solver, can synthesize information efficiently. Great teamwork and communication skills.

Detail oriented with an eye for clean design. Looking for a job where both my creativity and ingenuity can be expressed.

EDUCATION

MS, Computer Science | spec. in ML Sep 2020 – Jul 2022

Gr Georgia Institute of Technology **GPA 3.70**

BS, Computer Science Sep 2012 – Jun 2017

Touro College of Arts & Science GPA 3.95

* SKILLS

Node/Express

AMP

REST

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES **Python (•) JavaScript HTML** SCSS \odot Java \odot C# SQL WEB TECHNOLOGIES React/Redux \odot Angular \odot

 \odot

O

()

WORK EXPERIENCE

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

American Express, New York, NY

- Developed infrastructure and models for AiDa, the company's internal ML platform
- Handled development, devops, and QA tasks in a fast paced, multitime zone team
- Configured, tested, and deployed Docker containers for ML services such as invoice, reciept, and bank statement recognition
- Benchmarked and balanced load of services

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Jul 2019 - Mar 2022

Mar 2022 - present

American Express, New York, NY

- Developed improvements to frontend, middleware and backend of two credit card application web apps in a Scrum team of six.
- Finalist (2nd place) in internal Company-wide Hackathon.
- Built out automation and unit test suite for React web app.
- Served as rotating Scrum Master, running team meetings and helping clear blockers

FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER

Aug 2017 - Jul 2019

B&H Photo, New York, NY

- Collaborated on frontend development of Single Page Application in a team of 4 developers
- Led team statistically, completing over 50% of team's 2018 workload in assigned hours and tasks.
- Worked closely with Google as B&H's primary AMP developer, cutting page-load by over 75%.
- Implemented service worker for offline access & faster page transitions.
- Built 3 new pages and multiple JS components for the mobile website.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Dec 2016 - Aug 2017

Breta, New York, NY

- Created full-featured Ionic (Angular) mobile app as company's only dev.
- Produced and maintained project's joint SQL/SQLite database.
- Worked closely with designer and client in agile development paradigm

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Jun 2016 - Jan 2017

🟂 SmartMūv LLC, New York, NY

• Finished development and deployed native Android application.

PROJECTS

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Wrote Kinect-like control of games using Al pose estimation.
- Created multiple React/Redux, Node/Express applications.
- In the midst of developing React Native application
- Built 2 Android apps, one currently available on Play Store.
- Worked with team in agile paradigm recreating classic Pac Man game.
- Developed a chrome extension to skip silence in web media.

FREELANCE PROJECTS

- Designed, developed, and deployed 5+ responsive websites.
- Worked closely with clients in agile-like env of frequent deliverables.